Nicola Vece

+49 (0) 176 86 712 451 Nüßlerstraße, 44 me@nicovece.com 13088 Berlin www.nicovece.com Deutschland

To design something, you must know how to build it. As a graphic and digital product designer who has always had a foot in development, I have supported my clients in building their brands and businesses online and offline for twenty years. I still want to deepen my knowledge to be more helpful.

Work experience

10/2015 - Present

Front-end developer and digital product designer - Freelance

Salonbookingsystem OÜ. Tallinn, Estonia

- Supporting the company from the start in designing and developing its core product, creating a successful WordPress commercial plugin with thousands of active users.
- Lead front-end developer for WordPress-based applications
- UI/UX design consulting

09/2021 - Present

Digital product designer - Freelance

Beaver Lab S.r.l., Milan, Italy

- Design websites, microsites and marketing campaigns elements and artworks.
- Collaborate effectively with team members to ideate and conceptualize marketing campaigns.

11/2012 - 12/2022

Front-end developer and digital product designer - Freelance

Tomobikidesign di Paolo Barbagallo. Milan, Italy

- Designed digital products like websites, e-commerce, online catalogues and booking systems.
- Developed front-end and back-end of WordPress-based websites and web applications

07/2012 - 11/2018

Wordpress and Front-end developer, digital product designer - Partner WordpressChef. Ariano Irpino, Italy

 Developed front-end and back-end of WordPress-based websites and web applications

02/2007 - 12/2011

Graphic designer, Web department manager - Partner

Iknstudio. Ariano Irpino, Italy

- Managed projects and relationships with clients
- Implemented and maintained visual design systems for branding and communication.
- Led a four members team to design and develop websites and web applications.

01/2004 - 02/2007

Graphic designer - Trainee

Iknstudio. Ariano Irpino, Italy

Education

09/1996 - 07/2001

School of Architecture - Not graduated

University of Naples Federico II. Naples, Italy

Design skills

Development skills

Graphic design	Advanced	HTML	Advanced
Typography	Intermediate	CSS	Advanced
Layout deisgn	Advanced	Javascript	Intermediate
Brand and Identity design	Advanced	PHP	Intermediate
Image Editing and Retouching	Advanced	React	Novice
UI design	Advanced	Wordpress	Advanced
UX design	Intermediate	MySQL	Intermediate

Software skills

Languages

Adobe Creative Suite	Advanced	Italian	Native language
Figma	Intermediate	English	Between C1 Advanced and C2 Proficient
Sketch	Advanced	German	Between A1 Beginner and A2 Elementary
Sublime Text	Advanced		
Visual Studio Code	Intermediate		